PETER LOWE

WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

A professional web developer with a commitment to quality code and user experience. Motivated self paced learner with the ability to quickly pick up new languages and frameworks Experience working with both front and back end code.

EMPLOYMENT

Nov 2016 to Jul 2017 Reliasoft · Associate Software Engineer · Tucson, Arizona

> Full stack development and maintenance on two web applications built in asp.NET, HTML5 and Javacript with options for either SQL or Oracle databases. Within a few weeks of joining the company. I became the sole developer on one of the applications. Despite having no previous experience with .net, I was able to quickly familiarize myself with the framework and make significant contributions to the code base. Shipped thousands of lines of code and built numerous new features from the ground up.

May 2015 to Aug 2015 Sail Caribbean · Video Marketing · British Virgin Islands (BVI)

Shot, edited and produced a series of promotional videos for Sail Caribbean, a sailing summer camp based in the BVI. Coordinated all production activities in close collaboration to ensure the project was successfully completed on-time, under-budget and to the high standard expected by

Apr 2013 to May 2015 Koh Tao Pro Video · Underwater Videographer · Koh Tao, Thailand

Filmed and edited underwater videos in a range of challenging environments and with tight time constraints whilst ensuring a high guality final

Apr 2012 to Jan 2013 Agua-center Diving · SCUBA Instructor · Flamingo Beach, Costa Rica

Responsible for the training and safety of a diverse range of clientele. Produced daily dive plans that allowed clients to see the best that local

waters had to offer whilst staying within their level of skill and training.

Oct 2011 to Apr 2012 NeverDry Video · Underwater Videographer · Bocas Del Toro, Panama

I started out at NeverDry as a trainee and continued on as a full-time employee producing underwater videos for divers and promotional material

for local businesses

Sep 2010 to Oct 2011 Sailing Club Divers · Divemaster/Instructor · Nha Trang, Vietnam

EDUCATION

Dev Bootcamp

Nov 2015 - March 2016

Spent 19 weeks thoroughly immersed in learning Ruby, Rails, HTML, CSS, JavasScript, Jquery, Ajax and more. I worked closely with various teams to complete challenges, learn new technologies and produce apps. I gained a solid grounding in the skills required for full stack web development. Most importantly, I have mastered the ability to dive head first into new technologies and manage my own learning.

The University Of Manchester

Bachelor of Engineering Mechanical Engineering

Sept 2004 - June 2008

The engineering programs at Manchester focus heavily on group projects. This allowed me to develop excellent interpersonal skills and taught me to collaborate effectively with a wide range of people. My studies culminated in a dissertation on the simulation and optimization of tidal stream

turbines.

SKILLS

WEB DEVELOPMENT

Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Html5, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, Ajax, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Git, React.js, .Net, VB, Wordpress, PHP, Bootstrap, Foundation

VIDEO EDITING 3D MODELING AND ANIMATION

Premiere Pro, After Effects, Audition

Blender3D

PROJECTS

A user friendly interface for the Jepson Herbarium guide to vascular plants. The Jepson Herbarium is a dichotomous key designed to identify the plants of California produced by Berkeleys Jepson Herbarium. Despite being an excellent resource it is not easy or intuitive to use. With Robotanist we took the data from the Jepson Manual and created a full stack rails app that allows users to easily work their way through the dichotomous key and gives them guick and easy access to the glossary and other important features. I personally led the creation of the web crawling algorithm we used to capture the relevant data from the Jepson website and structure it as a tree in our database. The app was produced with permission from Berkeley by myself and three other Dev Bootcamp students as our final project. Berkeley has expressed interest in meeting with us in the next few weeks to discuss the future of the project. robotanist.herokuapp.com

Dive Directory is an open source web app designed to help scuba divers find great places to dive. The user can simply enter a location and dive directory will find dive sites near that location and display them on a map. Users can also post reviews of sites that they have dived and read reviews that other users have posted. I plan to add more features in the near future. thedivedirectory.co.uk